{"data":{"postgres":{"establishment":[{"establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","address":"2233 Park Avenue","zipcode":"48201-34","owner":"Sean Harrington","licenseNumber":"054046","licenseType":"Fixed Establishment","mostRecentLicenseDate":"5/7/2018","establishmentType":"Food Service Establishment","establishmentStatus":"Temporarily Closed","riskCategory":"High","reviewFrequencyDays":"180.0","geom":"0101000020E6100000E0E5790874C354C028DDD4E2412B4540","inspectionsByEstablishmentidList":[{"inspectionid":"42877","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","inspectionDate":"2018-07-13T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"124","pcount":"3","pfcount":"4","ccount":"2","criticalcount":"7","noncritical":"2","correctedcritical":"4","inCompliance":"No","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"42877","inspectionDate":"7/13/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","violationCode":"6-301.11","violationDescription":"Each HANDWASHING SINK or group of 2 adjacent HANDWASHING SINKS shall be provided with a supply of hand cleaning liquid, powder, or bar soap. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Soap","subItem":"at handsink kitchen","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"At hand sink","location":"HANDSINK(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-07-13T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide"},{"inspectionid":"42877","inspectionDate":"7/13/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","violationCode":"4-302.12","violationDescription":"(A) FOOD TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICES shall be provided and readily accessible for use in ensuring attainment and maintenance of FOOD temperatures as specified under Chapter 3. (Pf)   \r\n(B) A TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICE with a suitable small-diameter probe that is designed to measure the temperature of thin masses shall be provided and readily accessible to accurately measure the temperature in thin FOODS such as MEAT patties and FISH filets. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Food thermometer(s)","subItem":"probe","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide."},{"inspectionid":"42877","inspectionDate":"7/13/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","violationCode":"7-201.11","violationDescription":"POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIAL shall be stored so they can not contaminate FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE AND SINGLE-USE ARTICLES by:   \r\n(A) Separating the POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIAL by spacing or partitioning; (P) and   \r\n(B) Locating the POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIAL in an area that is not above FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE AND SINGLE-USE ARTICLES.  This paragraph does not apply to EQUIPMENT and UTENSIL cleaners and sanitizers that are stored in WAREWASHING areas for availability and convenience if the materials are stored to prevent contamination of FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES. (P)","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Poisonous/toxic material(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored over/with","subProblem":"Single-service/use items","location":"BAR","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-07-13T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store toxics below and away from all other items."},{"inspectionid":"42877","inspectionDate":"7/13/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","violationCode":"7-102.11","violationDescription":"Working containers used for storing POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIALS such as cleaners and SANITIZERS taken from bulk supplies shall be clearly and individually identified with the common name of the material. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Working containers-toxics","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not labeled as to content","subProblem":"","location":"BAR ( FIRST FLOOR)","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-08-29T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Label containers with common name."},{"inspectionid":"42877","inspectionDate":"7/13/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","violationCode":"5-202.13","violationDescription":"An air gap between the water supply inlet and the flood level rim of the PLUMBING FIXTURE, EQUIPMENT, or nonFOOD EQUIPMENT shall be at least twice the diameter of the water supply inlet and may not be less than 1 inch. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Air gap","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Less than twice the diameter of supply line","subProblem":"","location":"BASEMENT","subLocation":"","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide air gap that is twice the diameter of the drain line and no less than 1 inch."},{"inspectionid":"42877","inspectionDate":"7/13/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","violationCode":"4-602.13","violationDescription":"NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be cleaned at a frequency necessary to preclude accumulation of soil residues.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Nonfood contact surface(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"With accumulation of debris","subProblem":"","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Keep clean."},{"inspectionid":"42877","inspectionDate":"7/13/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","violationCode":"4-501.11","violationDescription":"EQUIPMENT shall be maintained in a state of repair and condition that meets the requirements of the code.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Equipment","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Do not meet requirements of rule","subProblem":"","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Repair/replace to meet requirements of rule."},{"inspectionid":"42877","inspectionDate":"7/13/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","violationCode":"3-501.16","violationDescription":"Except during preparation, cooking, or cooling, or when time is used as the public health control POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be maintained:\r\n(A)  135ºF or above, except that roasts properly cooked and cooled may be held              at a temperature of 130ºF; or (P)\r\n(B)   At 41ºF or less (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Cold food item(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored above 41 degrees F","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-07-13T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store below 41 degrees F."},{"inspectionid":"42877","inspectionDate":"7/13/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","violationCode":"6-501.111","violationDescription":"The presence of insects, rodents, and other pests shall be controlled to minimize their presence on the PREMISES.  by:\r\n(A) Routinely inspecting incoming shipments of FOOD and supplies; \r\n(B) Routinely inspecting the PREMISES for evidence of pests;\r\n(C) Using methods, if pests are found, such as trapping devices or other means of pest control as specified.(Pf) \r\n(D) Eliminating harborage conditions. \r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Pest(s)","subItem":"flies","problemDescription":"Present in facility","subProblem":"","location":"BAR(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Remove pests from facility."}]},{"inspectionid":"42879","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","inspectionDate":"2017-12-14T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"124","pcount":"2","pfcount":"4","ccount":"5","criticalcount":"6","noncritical":"5","correctedcritical":"3","inCompliance":"No","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"42879","inspectionDate":"12/14/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","violationCode":"4-602.13","violationDescription":"NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be cleaned at a frequency necessary to preclude accumulation of soil residues.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Nonfood contact surface(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"MOP SINK AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Clean."},{"inspectionid":"42879","inspectionDate":"12/14/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\r\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Physical facilities/structures","subItem":"floors","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"FLOOR","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Clean."},{"inspectionid":"42879","inspectionDate":"12/14/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","violationCode":"5-202.13","violationDescription":"An air gap between the water supply inlet and the flood level rim of the PLUMBING FIXTURE, EQUIPMENT, or nonFOOD EQUIPMENT shall be at least twice the diameter of the water supply inlet and may not be less than 1 inch. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Air gap","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Less than twice the diameter of supply line","subProblem":"","location":"WALK-IN COOLER","subLocation":"","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide air gap that is twice the diameter of the drain line and no less than 1 inch."},{"inspectionid":"42879","inspectionDate":"12/14/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","violationCode":"6-303.11","violationDescription":"Light of the proper intensity shall be provided as specified.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Lighting intensity","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not maintained","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Maintain in good repair"},{"inspectionid":"42879","inspectionDate":"12/14/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","violationCode":"4-501.11","violationDescription":"EQUIPMENT shall be maintained in a state of repair and condition that meets the requirements of the code.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Equipment components","subItem":"seals","problemDescription":"In poor repair","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"At the gasket/rubber lining","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"inspectionid":"42879","inspectionDate":"12/14/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","violationCode":"3-603.11","violationDescription":"If an animal FOOD such as  beef, EGGS, FISH, lamb, milk, pork, POULTRY, or shellfish is served or sold raw, undercooked, or without otherwise being processed to eliminate pathogens, either in a READY-TO-EAT form or as an ingredient in another READY-TO-EAT FOOD, the PERMIT HOLDER shall inform CONSUMERS of the significantly increased RISK of consuming such FOODS, by using menu advisories, brochures, lable statements, table tents, placards, or other effective written means. (Pf)\r\nFOOD LAW SEC 6149\r\n...The food establishment may provide the following statement on selection information so that it is made pulblicly available: \"Ask your server about menu items that are cooked to order or served raw.  Consuming raw or undercooked, meats, poultry, shellfish, or eggs may increase your risk of foodborne illness.\"\r\nThe statements must be in a minimum of 11 point font and in a color that provides a clear contrast to background.\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Menu advisories","subItem":"for raw or undercooked food(s)/ingredient(s) eggs","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"MENU(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide."},{"inspectionid":"42879","inspectionDate":"12/14/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","violationCode":"3-501.17","violationDescription":"(A)  READY-TO-EAT, POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  prepared and held refrigerated for more than 24 hours in a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT  shall be clearly marked at the time of preparation to indicate the date or day by which the FOOD shall be consumed. (Pf)\r\n(B)  A container of refrigerated, commercially prepared READY-TO-EAT POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  shall be clearly marked, at the time the original container is opened in a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT, to indicate the date or day by which the FOOD shall be consumed. (Pf)\r\n\r\nA date marking system that does not exceed 7 days, including date of preparation, or opening is to be used. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"In house prepared ready-to-eat potentially hazardous  food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Without date of consumption marking","subProblem":"","location":"BAR","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-12-14T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Discard"},{"inspectionid":"42879","inspectionDate":"12/14/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","violationCode":"6-501.111","violationDescription":"The presence of insects, rodents, and other pests shall be controlled to minimize their presence on the PREMISES.  by:\r\n(A) Routinely inspecting incoming shipments of FOOD and supplies; \r\n(B) Routinely inspecting the PREMISES for evidence of pests;\r\n(C) Using methods, if pests are found, such as trapping devices or other means of pest control as specified.(Pf) \r\n(D) Eliminating harborage conditions. \r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Pest(s)","subItem":"flies","problemDescription":"Present in facility","subProblem":"","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Remove pests from facility."},{"inspectionid":"42879","inspectionDate":"12/14/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","violationCode":"7-201.11","violationDescription":"POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIAL shall be stored so they can not contaminate FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE AND SINGLE-USE ARTICLES by:   \r\n(A) Separating the POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIAL by spacing or partitioning; (P) and   \r\n(B) Locating the POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIAL in an area that is not above FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE AND SINGLE-USE ARTICLES.  This paragraph does not apply to EQUIPMENT and UTENSIL cleaners and sanitizers that are stored in WAREWASHING areas for availability and convenience if the materials are stored to prevent contamination of FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES. (P)","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Poisonous/toxic material(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored over/with","subProblem":"Equipment/utensils","location":"BAR","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-12-14T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store toxics below and away from all other items."},{"inspectionid":"42879","inspectionDate":"12/14/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","violationCode":"6-301.14","violationDescription":"A sign or poster that notifies FOOD EMPLOYEES to wash their hands shall be provided at all HANDWASHING SINKS used by FOOD EMPLOYEES and shall be clearly visible to FOOD EMPLOYEES.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Handwashing signage","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"HANDSINK(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide."},{"inspectionid":"42879","inspectionDate":"12/14/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","violationCode":"7-102.11","violationDescription":"Working containers used for storing POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIALS such as cleaners and SANITIZERS taken from bulk supplies shall be clearly and individually identified with the common name of the material. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Working containers-toxics","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not labeled as to content","subProblem":"","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-12-14T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Label containers with common name."}]},{"inspectionid":"39046","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","inspectionDate":"2017-06-16T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"87","pcount":"0","pfcount":"0","ccount":"0","criticalcount":"0","noncritical":"0","correctedcritical":"0","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[]},{"inspectionid":"36915","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","inspectionDate":"2016-10-27T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"87","pcount":"2","pfcount":"0","ccount":"2","criticalcount":"2","noncritical":"2","correctedcritical":"2","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"36915","inspectionDate":"10/27/2016","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","violationCode":"3-101.11","violationDescription":"FOOD shall be safe, unADULTERATED and honestly presented. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Food","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not safe","subProblem":"","location":"BAR (UPPER)","subLocation":"Inside the Cooler (bar)","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2016-10-27T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Discard."},{"inspectionid":"36915","inspectionDate":"10/27/2016","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\r\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Physical facilities/structures","subItem":"floors","problemDescription":"With accumulation of debris","subProblem":"","location":"BASEMENT","subLocation":"On the Floor","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2016-11-10T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Keep clean."},{"inspectionid":"36915","inspectionDate":"10/27/2016","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","violationCode":"4-501.11","violationDescription":"EQUIPMENT shall be maintained in a state of repair and condition that meets the requirements of the code.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Equipment components","subItem":"seals","problemDescription":"In poor repair","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"At the gasket/rubber lining","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2016-11-10T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"inspectionid":"36915","inspectionDate":"10/27/2016","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3172","name":"Centaur Bar","violationCode":"5-202.13","violationDescription":"An air gap between the water supply inlet and the flood level rim of the PLUMBING FIXTURE, EQUIPMENT, or nonFOOD EQUIPMENT shall be at least twice the diameter of the water supply inlet and may not be less than 1 inch. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Air gap","subItem":"between supply line and flood rim of plumbing fixture","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"At the Over head spray unit ","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2016-11-10T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide air gap that is twice the diameter of the drain line and no less than 1 inch."}]}]}]}},"pageContext":{"eid":"3172"}}